Bless C. Obika

+2348038774980 | blesschinedumobika@gmail.com | Owerri Imo State Nigeria

Summary

Proficient software developer with deep understanding of both technical and business aspects of software development. Experience in developing web applications, desktop applications and mobile apps, with emphasis on clean code, maintainability, security and performance. Able to communicate with team members at all levels, provide direction, and remain open to feedback

Experience

Bivindi | Douala littoral

Software Engineering intern | 01/2023 - 05/2023

- Developed a novel technology platform that enables the company to sell more products and services.
- Conducted 10 interviews over the course of 2 months to hire candidates for the software engineering internship program.
- Collected data and conducted 10 usability tests, redesigning the user experience to increase the number of sales leads generated per month by 13%.
- Planned and implemented a webinar series to train 30 junior web developers

TEC-Labs | Douala Littoral

Software Developer | 08/2022 - 12/2022

- Performed software testing, provided 24/7 support to clients, and developed plans for future software development
- Maintained software products including programs, webpages, and databases
- Helped increase the adoption of new software tools and techniques that increased the effectiveness of a Web application

ZTAD | Bamenda Northwest

Software developer | 11/2021 - 05/2022

• Developed applications for client enterprise and individual firms.• Managed servers and web services.• Managed project executions.

Civil Salt | Bamenda Cameroon

Desktop Developer | 03/2021 - 11/2021

Directed a team of junior Devs in accomplishing solid desktop applications for businesses and educational sectors. Guided the development of banking systems that granted users the ease to carry out various transactions at their own comfort

Further Solutions Group | NorthWest Bamenda

Front-End Developer | 07/2020 - 01/2021

Improved the scalability of the product by creating a new product component that completed a full integration test in less than one dayLed the development of a new product that allowed users to complete tasks on their own. Maintained accurate inventory levels and improved customer service through the implementation of a multi- channel ordering system.

Skills

JavaScript, Node.js, ReactJS, C#, ASP.NET, .NET, .NET CORE, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Dart, Flutter, UI/UX Design

Education

AFRIITECH | Bamenda Cameroon

Software Engineering | 04/2020

Completed courses in computer engeneering, marketing, and statistics

Languages

English, French

links

LinkedIn <u>Bless Obika</u>